<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<configentry>
    <keyword>TARGET</keyword>

    <scope>NODE</scope> 
    <anchor>NODE_TARGET</anchor>

    <definition>TARGET

        <meta>targetspec</meta>
    </definition>

    <definition>TARGET

        <meta>targetspec</meta>

        <meta>targetspec</meta>
    </definition>

    <definition>TARGET

        <meta>targetspec</meta>

        -

        <meta>targetspec</meta>
    </definition>

    <definition>TARGET

        <meta>targetspec</meta>

        n*

        <meta>targetspec</meta>
    </definition>

    <definition>TARGET "<meta>targetspec</meta>"
    </definition>

    <description xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Specifies where to look for the current "throughput" information for this
        NODE. You can also specify multiple targets, which will then be added together
        to make the aggregate result which is then displayed. Specify the targets on one
        TARGET line, seperated with a space. If a targetspec starts with a '-', then
        it's value will be <i>subtracted</i> from the final result instead.</p>

        <p>Also, if a targetspec starts with a number, then a *, then it's used a
        scaling factor on the result. You can do basic maths with this, especially if
        you remember that multiplying by a number below 1 is the same as dividing by 1
        divided by that number (0.5* is the same as divide by 2).</p>

        <p>For both the '-' and '*' options,
        <em>there must be no spaces</em> between any modifiers and the actual target
        string after it.</p>

        <p>It's important to note, especially for NODEs, that the value that is used
        does not have to be bandwidth. You can use data for temperature, session-counts,
        CPU usage or anything else you can get data for.</p>

        <p>The actual contents of the
        <em>targetspec</em> depend on the data source plugins that are available.
        <a href="targets.html">The standard plugins are documented here</a>.</p>

        <p>To help with filenames that can contain spaces, or for the external script
        data source, you can enclose the entire targetspec in double-quotes (") to show
        that it is a single targetspec.
        <em>The quotes must be around the whole targetspec, including any
        prefixes.</em> </p>
    </description>

    <changes>
        <change version="0.96">Added quotes option for targets with spaces.
        </change>

        <change version="0.96">Added scale factors for all datasources.
        </change>

        <change version="0.91">Added 'negative' datasources.
        </change>

        <change version="0.9">Added plugin data sources, node targets, and added new
        plugins.
        </change>

        <change version="0.8">Added ability to specify multiple targets. Added
        tab-delimited data source. Added 'ignore' DS name.
        </change>

        <change version="0.5">Added ability to specify DS names.
        </change>
    </changes>

    <examples>
        <example><caption>Using multiple data sources for one link</caption>

            <content>TARGET link1a.rrd link1b.rrd
            </content>
        </example>

        <example><caption>Taking the input from one file, and output from
        another</caption>

            <content>TARGET poot.rrd:-:DS1 poot2.rrd:DS0:-
            </content>
        </example>
    </examples>
</configentry>
