<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<configentry>
    <keyword>FONTDEFINE</keyword>

    <scope>GLOBAL</scope>

    <anchor>GLOBAL_FONTDEFINE</anchor>

    <definition>FONTDEFINE

        <meta>fontnumber</meta>

        <meta>gdfontfile</meta>
    </definition>

    <definition>FONTDEFINE

        <meta>fontnumber</meta>

        <meta>ttffontfile</meta>

        <meta>fontsize</meta>
    </definition>

    <description xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Defines a custom font to be used for text within the map.</p>

        <p>By default, the GD library used by Weathermap has 5 fonts, numbered 1-5.
        FONTDEFINE allows you to define new font numbers, and link them to fonts in two
        other formats.</p>

        <p>The first format is 'GD fonts', which are a bitmapped format used by GD
        alone. They are not scalable, and are also platform-specific (they use a
        different byte-order depending on the host). You should specify the full
        filename including any extensions.</p>

        <p>The second format is TrueType fonts, which are scalable, standard and
        generally a lot nicer! This time, you need to specify the size that the font
        should be rendered at. The size is in pixels. You can load the same font into
        multiple fontnumbers with different sizes to use in different parts of a map.</p>

        <p>The freetype library used in PHP makes a somewhat complex set of rules for
        where it will search for truetype fonts. The two easiest options are:

        <ul><li>Use the full absolute path to your .ttf file</li>
            <li>Keep your .ttf files in the Weathermap directory, and use the first part
            of the filename only, with no '.ttf' on the end.</li>						
        </ul>
		
		<p><em>If you have a font in the Weathermap directory as above and it's not loading, also
		try: ./FontName.ttf</em></p>

        The full set of rules is
        <a href="http://www.boutell.com/gd/manual2.0.33.html#gdImageStringFT">available
        here</a></p>

        <p>Regardless of the format, the newly defined font can be used anywhere that
        you'd normally use a font number (for example, BWFONT or KEYFONT).
        </p>
    </description>

    <examples>
        <example><caption>Defining a new Truetype font, with the font file in the
        weathermap directory</caption>

            <content>FONTDEFINE 10 VeraBd 16
            </content>
        </example>
    </examples>

    <changes>
        <change version="0.8">First added FONTDEFINE
        </change>
    </changes>
</configentry>