<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<configentry>
    <keyword>ICON</keyword>

    <scope>NODE</scope>

    <anchor>NODE_ICON</anchor>

    <definition>ICON

        <meta>iconimagefile</meta>
    </definition>

    <definition>ICON

        <meta>maxwidth</meta>

        <meta>maxheight</meta>

        <meta>iconimagefile</meta>
    </definition>

    <definition>ICON none
    </definition>

    <description xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Specifies an icon to use for the node.</p>

        <p>The filename can either be a full path to the image, or a relative one. </p>

        <p>The icon file must be in PNG, JPEG or GIF format. Alpha-transparency within
        the icon should be honoured by Weathermap for PNG icons, to create irregular
        shapes.</p>

        <p>If you specify the word 'none' as the icon filename, then no icon is used.
        This is useful if you have specified an ICON in the DEFAULT NODE, and want to
        override that for a few special cases.</p>

        <p>There are some special icon filenames that can be used to generate an icon
        image without using an external file. These all
        <em>require</em> you to specify a <em>maxwidth</em> and
        <em>maxheight</em> which are then used as the size of the icon. The 'magic
        filenames' are:

        <ul><li>'box' - to produce a square cornered box.</li><li>'rbox'
        - to produce a round-cornered box</li><li>'round'
        - to produce a circle or ellipse.</li>

            <li>'inpie' &amp; 'outpie'
            - to produce a pie-chart of either the in or out value relative to it's
            maximum. The colouring options on this are likely to change in a future
            version.</li>

            <li>'nink'
            - to produce a circular 'yin-yang'-style symbol, with each half showing the
            in and out values. The colouring options on this are likely to change in a
            future version.</li>
        </ul>The colours for these "artificial icons" are specified using the
        AICONFILLCOLOR and AICONOUTLINECOLOR keywords.</p>

        <p>The second form allows you to specify a maximum width and height for the
        icon. If the PNG file that you specify is bigger or smaller than this size, then
        it is automatically scaled up (or down) in proportion, so that it fits into a
        box of the size you specify.</p>

        <p>The size of the icon image is used by LABELOFFSET to decided how far to move
        the label, if you use compass-point offsets.</p>

        <p>The text for the filename can contain
        <a href="advanced.html#tokens">special tokens</a> to select an icon based on
        map data.</p>

        <p>You can adjust the colour of the icon according to a SCALE, by using
        USEICONSCALE, if you are using the PHP GD library (the function required is not
        present in the main GD library).</p>
    </description>

    <changes>
        <change version="0.96">Added inpie, outpie and nink.
        </change>

        <change version="0.95">Added Artificial Icon support - round, rbox and box.
        </change>

        <change version="0.95">Added Icon colourising support.
        </change>

        <change version="0.9">Added 'special token' support.
        </change>

        <change version="0.9">Added JPEG and GIF support.
        </change>

        <change version="0.9">Added special icon 'none', and automatic scaling.
        </change>
    </changes>
</configentry>